Independence Day. It wasn't just an alien invasion movie. It
was a cultural reset. The epic scale, the iconic moments,
the sheer summer blockbuster spectacle. But even the most die-hard
fans might not know all the secrets hidden beneath the
explosions. Get ready as we countdown 20 hidden facts about
Independence Day. 10. Miniatures Over CGI. Forget CGI for a
moment. Independence Day blew up the world the old-fashioned way:
with meticulously crafted miniatures. From the towering New York skyline
to that unforgettable White House inferno, every explosion was a
practical effect. Volkar Angel and his team spent months wiring
those tiny buildings with charges and filming in slow motion,
turning destruction into an art form. Fun fact: When the
White House scene was filmed, the press was invited. One
push of a button, and a perfect replica was gone.
It even won an Oscar for best visual effects, marking
the end of Hollywood's reliance on practical effects.